starwest-botanicals.com 2019-02-26

# Privacy Policy

Starwest Botanicals, Inc., collects only the information required to process your order, along with basic information about how our site is being used so that we can continue to improve it for you. We will not share, rent, lend, or sell your information to anyone. 

To ensure that your information is secure, we use the latest SSL technology (the best encryption technology currently available) to encrypt all of your order details, including name, billing address, and credit card information as they are in transit. If you would like to read more about our privacy and security policies, click on the links below, and feel free to contact us with any additional questions you might have. 

  1. What personally identifiable information is being collected?
  2. How is the information being used? 
  3. What are cookies and how do we use them? 
  4. What kind of security procedures are in place to protect personally identifiable information? 

* * *

## What personally identifiable information is being collected?

In order for Starwest to provide you with the products or services that you have requested, you may be asked to provide us with personally identifiable information. For example, when you place an order, you will be asked for your shipping and billing addresses, your e-mail address, and your credit card number or other payment-related information. If you request our newsletters or send an inquiry to one of our customer service representatives, we will store a record of your request, along with your e-mail address, so that we can respond accordingly. In addition, our Web servers track various technical details about your visit, such as your computer's IP address and which pages you visited. However, that information does not typically contain any personally identifiable information about you and is only used internally to improve our products and services. Back To Top

## How is the information being used? 

The information we collect is used to provide the products and services that you have requested. For example, we will use the e-mail address you provide when you place an order to send you information about that order, such as confirmation of your order and tracking information when it is shipped. You are given the opportunity to opt-in and opt-out of any additional communication from Starwest, such as our newsletter and product specials, and can do so at any time by choosing the "Modify Profile" option that appears at the top of your screen while you are logged into your Starwest-Botanicals.com account. The information we collect is also used to improve the content of our Web site and notify you of problems with your requests. Back To Top

## What are cookies and how do we use them? 

A cookie is a piece of information that is sent to your computer's hard drive to help us recognize you when you return to our site. Cookies are used as a standard practice by many sites. These types of cookies cannot identify an individual user specifically, such as by name or address, unless the cookie data is attached to personally identifiable information, such as online registration. An example of how cookie work: You start to place items in your shopping cart, but then have to leave our site or shut off your computer, if you return to our site within a designated period of time, the cookie enables our site to recognize that you have returned, and all the items you placed in your cart during the earlier session will still be there. 

We also use cookies to determine the number of unique visitors to our site and observe our visitors navigation throughout the site. This helps us identify ways to improve your shopping experience. 

As important as cookies are to our site, we understand that this might make you uncomfortable. If you would prefer to not accept cookies from our site, or any other site, you can modify the settings on your web browser to block them. Please refer to your browser's online help feature, or the user's manual, for instructions on how to do this. 

We also use third party vendors, including Google and Facebook, to show our ads on sites on the internet. The third party vendors we utilize, including Google, may use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website. Users may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page.](https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/) (Alternatively you can opt out of third party cookies for a variety of advertisers, most of which we do not use, by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)) 

This site uses ClickTale web analytics service. ClickTale may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity as well as text you type in this website. This site does not use ClickTale to collect any personally identifiable information entered in this website. ClickTale does not track your browsing habits across web sites which do not use ClickTale services. For more information see Privacy Policy for Information Collected by the ClickTale Web Analytics Service. We are using the information collected by ClickTale service to improve the user experience for all visitors. You can choose to disable the Service at [the ClickTale opt-out page](https://www.clicktale.net/disable.html). 

Third parties (such as Facebook) may use cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to collect or receive information from our website and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target ads. You can opt-out of the collection and use of information for ad targeting at [www.aboutads.info/choices](https://www.aboutads.info/choices). Back To Top

## What kind of security procedures are in place to protect personally identifiable information?

Protecting your personal information is extremely important to us. To this end, Starwest uses the latest in Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to communicate with your web browser. This technology allows for the encryption of all personal information passed between our servers and your web browser, including your name, address, and credit card number. SSL technology is utilized both when placing orders through our store and when logging into your existing account on our website to modify any of your personal information. 

You can confirm that your connection is secure by looking in the lower right-hand corner of your browser window. If you see an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending on your browser), the SSL is active and your connection is secure. You can also look at the web address (URL) displayed near the top of your browser to see if your connection is secure. If secure, it will have an 'https' prefix, rather than the normal 'http' prefix. Please note that SSL will not activate until you log into an existing account on our site or begin the checkout process once you have completed your shopping. 

Back To Top
